Guide to the Stanford University, Controller's Office, Financial Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Controller's Office, financial records
1909-1957
SC0100
Stanford University. Controller's Office.
3.5 Linear feet
Working copies of University budgets (1909-1918; 1945-1957); materials regarding salaries (working drafts and correspondence); and financial data from the late 1920's and early 1930's regarding Stanford University owned properties, primarily located on campus.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Controller's Office, 1972.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
This collection of financial records includes departmental budgets with some annotations and correspondence, 1909-1921 and 1945-1957; salary rolls with correspondence and annotations, 1908-1915 and 1918-1921; and memoranda, balance sheets, and other materials pertaining to Stanford-owned properties, on campus and elsewhere, 1930-1934.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Controller's Office.; Campus Planning.; Universities and colleges--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Finance.
Collection Contents
- Detailed record of departmental appropriates as prepared by the President and acted on by Board of Trustees, pages 1-80, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Detailed record of departmental appropriates as prepared by the President and acted on by Board of Trustees, pages 81-166, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Detailed record of departmental appropriates as prepared by the President and acted on by Board of Trustees, pages 167-end, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Recommendations and Estimates of Departmental Heads for 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget data, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Budget of President of the University for 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- President’s Budget ("no. 3168"), 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Budget (1 of 2), 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Budget (2 of 2), 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Budget, departments by alpha: A-H, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Budget, departments by alpha: L-Z, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Budget data, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Budget, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Budget data departments by alpha: A-E, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Budget data departments by alpha: G-O, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Budget data departments by alpha: P-Z, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Budget (annotated) departments by alpha: A-E, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Budget (annotated) departments by alpha: G-P, 19199-1920 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Budget (annotated) departments by alpha: R-Z, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Budget (annotated) Administrative units, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Budget (annotated) departments by alpha: A-L, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Budget (annotated) departments by alpha: M-Z, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Budget (annotated) Summaries, etc., 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- President’s Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- President’s Office revised budget, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Budgeted salaries and expense as of Sept. 1, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Departmental Budget, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Departmental Budget (Budget Section), 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Departmental Budget, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Departmental Budget (General Fund Section), 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Departmental Budget (Budget Section), 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Departmental Budget (Budget Section), 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Departmental Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Departmental Budget, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Departmental Budget (Mr. Worley), 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Tentative salary roll, 1908-1909 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Salary roll, 1910-1911 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Salary roll, 1911-1912 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Salary roll, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Salary roll, 1913-1914 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Salary roll, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Salaries, miscellaneous data, survey, etc., 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Salary roll, 1918-1919 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Salary roll, 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Salary roll, 1920-1921 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous memoranda re procedures for handling real estate finances, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Accounting instructions [correspondence re money owned Stanford University on leases, loans, etc.], 1931-1934 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Monthly balance sheets, 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Monthly balance sheets, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Record of monthly notices [mailed to Stanford’s debtors], 1934 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Trial balance sheets, 1943-1934 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Interest accrual sheets [re mortgages held by Stanford], 1931-1934 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Financial data re Stanford university properties – faculty leases, Palo Alto Farm, sororities, etc., 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Data re campus residence and mortgages/loans, 1930-1932 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Financial data re Stanford-owned, non-campus properties, 1929-1934 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Continuation certificates and Report to the Board, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Trial balances, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 12)